{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "when did God create the heavens and the earth?",
      "answer": "in the beginning was everything created by God.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:1"
    },
    {
      "question": "what did God create in the beginning?",
      "answer": "God created all the the heavens and the earth in the beginning.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:1"
    },
    {
      "question": "who created everything in the beginning?",
      "answer": "God",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:1"
    },
    {
      "question": "what was the earth like in the beginning?",
      "answer": "The earth was formless and empty.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:2"
    },
    {
      "question": "was the Holy Spirit present on earth in the beginning?",
      "answer": "the spirit of God was hovering over the waters before the earth was ordered.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:2"
    },
    {
      "question": "how did God create light?",
      "answer": "God spoke light into existence.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:3"
    },
    {
      "question": "how did God perceive light, after he created it?",
      "answer": "God saw it that light was good after he spoke it into existence.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:4"
    },
    {
      "question": "where does it say that light is good?",
      "answer": "In Genesis chapter 1, verse 4, it is written that God saw that the light was good after he created it.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:4"
    },
    {
      "question": "what did God do on the first day of creation?",
      "answer": "God created light, and separated it from darkness. After evening and morning, the first day was complete.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:5"
    },
    {
      "question": "when did God name light \"day\" and darkness \"night\"?",
      "answer": "God named light \"day\" and darkness \"night\" on the first day creation, after he created light.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:5"
    },
    {
      "question": "when did God create light?",
      "answer": "God created light on the first day of creation.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:5"
    },
    {
      "question": "how did God create the skies?",
      "answer": "And God said, \"Let there be vault between waters to separate waters from waters, so God made a space that is now the atmosphere.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:6"
    },
    {
      "question": "did God separate waters that were on top of waters when creating the skies?",
      "answer": "Yes, the bible says that to create the skies God separated the waters and put a vault between them.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:7"
    },
    {
      "question": "how do we know that the space God made between the waters was the sky?",
      "answer": "after God created the vault (expanse, space) between the waters above and below he called it sky.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:7-Genesis 1:8" 
    },
    {
      "question": "what day did God create the sky on earth.",
      "answer": "God created the skies on earth on the second day of creation.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:8"
    },
    {
      "question": "how did God create the land we walk on?",
      "answer": "On the third day of creation God commanded the waters be gathered to one place, and dry ground appeared.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:9"
    },
    {
      "question": "did God name the land and sea?",
      "answer": "After creating dry ground, God named it \"land\", and after gathering the waters he called them \"seas\".",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:10"
    },
    {
      "question": "how did God create plants and trees?",
      "answer": "God spoke, and commanded the dry land to produce vegetation.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:11"
    },
    {
      "question": "how did the dry land respond to God's command to produce vegetation?",
      "answer": "When God commanded, the dry land responded by producing fruit bearing trees and vegetation that had seeds.  Creation always responds according to God\"s will and decrees.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:11-Genesis 1:12" 
    },
    {
      "question": "In what day did God create the skies, seas and vegetation?",
      "answer": "God created the skies along with the seas, dry land, and vegetation on the third day of creation.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:9-Genesis 1:13" 
    },
    {
      "question": "what was God's command for creating the sun and the moon.",
      "answer": "In Genesis chapter 1 verse 14 we find God's command for creating the sun and the moon.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:14"
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the purpose for the sun and moon.",
      "answer": "God purpose for the sun and moon were and still are to bring light over the earth.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:15-Genesis 1:18" 
    },
    {
      "question": "did God make the sun, moon and stars?",
      "answer": "God made the sun and moon to and stars, each with its purpose, to bring light to day time and night time. ",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:16"
    },
    {
      "question": "does God want to separate the light from darkness?",
      "answer": "In God's perfect creation, his will is to separate light from darkness.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:18"
    },
    {
      "question": "when did God create the sun, moon and stars",
      "answer": "God created the sun, moon and stars on the fourth day",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:14-Genesis 1:19" 
    },
    {
      "question": "What was God command to create fish and birds",
      "answer": "God's command to create fish and birds can be found in Genesis chapter 1 verse 20.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:20"
    },
    {
      "question": "did God create the all the creatures in the sea, and all the creautres that fly?",
      "answer": "on the fifth day of creation God created all animals that live in the sea and all the animals that fly in the sky.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:21"
    },
    {
      "question": "did God bless the fish and birds?",
      "answer": "After creating all the creatures in the sea and all the creatures that fly in the sky he blessed them.  God commanded them to increase in number to fill the earth and sea.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:23"
    },
    {
      "question": "when did God create all the sea creatures and birds of the sky?",
      "answer": "God created all the sea creatures and the birds on the fifth day of creation.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:23"
    },
    {
      "question": "what was God command to create the walk on the ground?",
      "answer": "you can find God's command for the land to produce all the creatures that walk in the ground in the book of Genesis chapter 1 verse 25.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:24"
    },
    {
      "question": "did God create the animals that walk on the land?",
      "answer": "God created all the animals of the land.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:25"
    },
    {
      "question": "did God create man according to his image?",
      "answer": "God declared man would be according to his likeness, and image.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:26-Genesis 1:27" 
    },
    {
      "question": "did God give mankind authority over all the animals?",
      "answer": "When creating mankind, God declared that they would rule over all fish, bird and animal that walked in the ground.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:26"
    },
    {
      "question": "how many genders did God create for mankind?",
      "answer": "God created two genders for mankind, male and female.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:27"
    },
    {
      "question": "does God want mankind to populate the earth?",
      "answer": "God commanded mankind to be fruitful, increase in number and populate the earth?",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:28"
    },
    {
      "question": "did God intend mankind to rule over all the animals?",
      "answer": "When blessing mankind, God stated mankind should rule over all the animals in the world.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:28"
    },
    {
      "question": "what did God intend mankind to eat?",
      "answer": "God gave all the plants with seeds, and trees with fruit that have seeds as food for mankind.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:29"
    },
    {
      "question": "what did God intend all the animals in the earth to eat?",
      "answer": "God gave all green plant as food for all the animals on earth.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:30"
    },
    {
      "question": "when did God create mankind?",
      "answer": "God created mankind on the sixth day of creation.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:26-Genesis 1:31" 
    },
    {
      "question": "when did God create all the animals that walk on land?",
      "answer": "God created all the animals that walk on the ground on the sixth day of creation, along with mankind.",
      "verse": "Genesis 1:24-Genesis 1:25, Genesis 1:31"
    },
    {
      "question": "was creation ever completed?",
      "answer": "After the sixth day of creation, it the bible declares that everything was finished.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:1"
    },
    {
      "question": "what was completed when God finished creation?",
      "answer": "All the heavens and the earth and all the hosts of them were completed",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:1"
    },
    {
      "question": "when did God rest after finishing all of creation?",
      "answer": "On the seventh day, good ended his work and rested.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:2"
    },
    {
      "question": "how long did it take God to finish everything?",
      "answer": "It took God six days to finish the work of creation.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:2"
    },
    {
      "question": "why is the seventh day considered holy?",
      "answer": "The seventh day is holy because God rested from all his work, and he blessed it and made it holy.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:3"
    },
    {
      "question": "how was the ground watered before man was created?",
      "answer": "Before God sent rain, the ground was watered by streams that rose from the ground.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:5-Genesis 2:6" 
    },
    {
      "question": "what did God use to form man?",
      "answer": "God used the dust from the ground to form man.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:7"
    },
    {
      "question": "how did God form man?",
      "answer": "God took dust from the ground and breathed into his nostrils the breath of life.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:7"
    },
    {
      "question": "did God plant a garden in Eden?",
      "answer": "the Lord planted a garden in the east, in Eden.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:8"
    },
    {
      "question": "in what direction was the garden of Eden placed?",
      "answer": "the Lord planted the garden of Eden to the east.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:8"
    },
    {
      "question": "did God place man in the garden of Eden?",
      "answer": "God placed man in the garden of Eden?",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:8"
    },
    {
      "question": "what kind of trees did God put in the garden of Eden?",
      "answer": "God made all kinds of beautiful trees in the garden of Eden that were good for food.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:9"
    },
    {
      "question": "what was in the middle of the garden of Eden?",
      "answer": "in the middle of the garden God placed the tree of life, and the tree of the knowledge of good and evil",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:9"
    },

    {
      "question": "where is the tree of life located?",
      "answer": "The tree of life is located in the middle of the garden of Eden.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:9"
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the tree of life?",
      "answer": "the tree of life is on of the two trees God placed in the middle of the garden of Eden.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:9"
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the tree of knowledge of good and evil?",
      "answer": "the tree of life is on of the two trees God placed in the middle of the garden of Eden.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:9"
    },
    {
      "question": "how was the garden of Eden watered?",
      "answer": "a river flowed from the garden of Eden and watered it.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:10"
    },
    {
      "question": "did the river that watered the garden of Eden separate into other rivers?",
      "answer": "the river that watered the garden of Eden separated into four other rivers; they are Pishon, Gihon, Tigris and Euphrates.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:10-Genesis 2:14" 
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the Pishon river?",
      "answer": "When the river that waters the garden of Eden separates into four main rivers, the first is the Pishon river.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:11"
    },
    {
      "question": "where does the Pishon river travel trough?",
      "answer": "The Pishon river travels through the entire land of Havilah.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:11"
    },
    {
      "question": "is there gold iin Havilah?",
      "answer": "The gold in the land of Havilah is good, along with resin and onyx.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:11-Genesis 2:12" 
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of natural resources are found in Havilah?",
      "answer": "Havilah has gold, resin and onyx of good quality.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:11-Genesis 2:12" 
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the Gihon river?",
      "answer": "When the river that waters the garden of Eden separates into four main rivers, the second is the Gihon river.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:13"
    },
    {
      "question": "where does the Gihon river travel through?",
      "answer": "The Gihon river travels through the entire land of Cush.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:13"
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the Tigris river?",
      "answer": "When the river that waters the garden of Eden separates into four main rivers, the third is the Tigris river.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:14"
    },
    {
      "question": "where does the Tigris river travel through?",
      "answer": "The Tigris river travels through the east side of Ashur.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:14"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Euphrates river?",
      "answer": "When the river that waters the garden of Eden separates into four main rivers, the fourth is the Euphrates river.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:14"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why did God put man in the garden of Eden?",
      "answer": "The Lord put man in the garden of Eden to work it and care for it.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:15"
    },
    {
      "question": "what did man eat in the garden of Eden?",
      "answer": "man was free to eat from any tree in the garden, except from the tree of the knowledge of good and evil. ",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:15"
    },
    {
      "question": "what was man not allowed to eat in the garden of Eden?",
      "answer": "Man was not allowed to eat from the tree of knowledge of good and evil.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:17"
    },
    {
      "question": "was man allowed to eat from the tree of knowledge of good and evil?",
      "answer": "Man was not allowed to eat from the tree of knowledge of good and evil.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:17"
    },
    {
      "question": "what would happen to man if he ate from the fruit of the tree of knowledge of good and evil?",
      "answer": "God declared that if man ate from the fruit of the tree of knowledge of good and evil, he would certainly die. ",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:17"
    },
    {
      "question": "does God want man to be alone?",
      "answer": "The Lord God said, \"It is not good for man to be alone.\"",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:18"
    },
    {
      "question": "what did God first do to aid mans' loneliness?",
      "answer": "God brought all the animals of the land and birds of the sky to Adam, so he could name them.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:19"
    },
    {
      "question": "did Adam give names to all the animals?",
      "answer": "God gave Adam the task of naming all the animals.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:19"
    },
    {
      "question": "was any suitable helper found within the animals for Adam?",
      "answer": "There was no suitable helper found in any animal.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:20"
    },
    {
      "question": "how did God remove a rib from Adam?",
      "answer": "God made Adam fall into a deep sleep, and took a rib from him.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:21"
    },
    {
      "question": "what did God remove from Adam when he put him to sleep?",
      "answer": "God removed a rib from Adam after putting him in a deep sleep.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:21"
    },
    {
      "question": "why did God remove a rib from Adam?",
      "answer": "God removed a rib from Adam to create a woman.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:22"
    },
    {
      "question": "what did God create with Adam's rib?",
      "answer": "God used Adams's rib to create a women.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:22"
    },
    {
      "question": "what did adam say when he saw Eve?",
      "answer": "When Adam saw eve he said, \"This is now bone of my bone and flesh of my flesh.\" and named her women",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:23"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why does man leave his father and mother?",
      "answer": "Man will leave his father and mother to become one with his wife.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:24"
    },
    {
      "question": "what happens when a man and a women unite?",
      "answer": "When a man and a women unite, they become one flesh.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:24"
    },
    {
      "question": "were Adam and Eve naked in the garden of Eden?",
      "answer": "Adam and Eve were naked in garden of Eden, but they were not ashamed.",
      "verse": "Genesis 2:25"
    },
    {
      "question": "was Adam and Eve ashamed of being naked in the garden of Eden?",
      "verse": "Even thou Adam and Eve were naked in the garden of Eden, they were not ashamed.",
      "answer": "Genesis 2:25"
    },
    {
      "question": "who was the craftiest animal the Lord had made?",
      "answer": "Of all the animals, the serpent was the craftiest animal the Lord had made.",
      "verse": "Genesis 3:1"
    },
    {
      "question": "did Eve know she was not suppose to eat the fruit of the three of knowledge of good and evil?",
      "answer": "Eve knew that they were not allowed to touch or eat of the tree that is in the middle of the garden.",
      "verse": "Genesis 3:2-Genesis 3:3" 
    },
    {
      "question": "how did the snake trick Eve into eating the fruit.",
      "answer": "The serpent told Eve that if they ate of the fruit of knowledge they would not die.",
      "verse": "Genesis 3:4"
    },
    {
      "question": "who did the snake trick into eating the fruit?",
      "answer": "The serpent tricked Eve into eating the fruit of knowledge of good and evil.",
      "verse": "Genesis 3:4"
    },
    {
      "question": "what would happen to Eve if she ate of the fruit of knowledge according to the snake?",
      "answer": "The snake said that she would not die, and she would be like God.",
      "verse": "Genesis 3:4-Genesis 3:5" 
    },
    {
      "question": "what did Eve see when she looked at the fruit of knowledge?",
      "answer": "Eve saw that fruit was pleasing to look at and desirable for gaining knowledge.",
      "verse": "Genesis 3:6"
    },
    {
      "question": "did Eve give to her husband Adam some of the fruit to eat?",
      "answer": "After eating of the fruit of knowledge, she gave some to her husband Adam.",
      "verse": "Genesis 3:6"
    }
  ]
}